Guide to the Fales Manuscript Collection circa 1700-2000 MSS.001
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Manuscript Collection
circa 1700-2000
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales, DeCoursey, 1888-1966
MSS.001
118 Linear Feet
The Fales Manuscript collection is made up of some 50,000 items, much of which was assembled by DeCoursey Fales from 1908-1966 and donated to NYU. The provenance of the materials is complicated, however. Following Fales' death in 1966, other collections and purchases were added into the Fales Manuscripts collection. We do not have a comprehensive listing of what Fales owned and what the library later purchased after his death. The collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, drawings, photographs, realia, ephemera, and other materials primarily about English and American authors from 1700 to the present. There are special strenths in the Victorian, Edwardian, English 1890s, and Transition Period writers.
Provenance
The Fales Manuscripts Collection was begun by DeCoursey Fales sometime after he began collecting books in 1908-09. By 1957 when Fales donated the collection to NYU, it had grown to over 15,000 items. He continued to build the collection until his death in 1966, by which time it is believed that the collection housed some 50,000 items. Unfortunately, subsequent curators did not treat the Fales Manuscript Collection as a separate collection with a distinct provenance. Instead, they added new acquisitions into the collection, sometimes incorporating whole small archives, such as the Provincetown Players Archive, the Tom Clark Papers, the Frank Harris Papers, the Smith and Austen-Leigh Papers, and many others. The collection was processed in varying ways over the years. At some early point manuscripts style processing at the item level was done for letters A-C—the collection is organized alphabetically by author. This processing was very incomplete, though cards still exist for the initial portions of the collection. At some later date, the collection was foldered with several authors in each folder, making it difficult to use the papers and to maintain control over the holdings. The current processing was undertaken to refolder the collection, account for all materials currently held, and create a finding aid that would adequately reflect the collection as it stands today. In addition, we have preserved the original box numbering so that past citations to the box numbers are still identifiable. As much as possible where distinct collections have been identified within the Fales Manuscripts Collection, separate finding aids have been created for those portions of the collection. These collections are still filed within the Fales Manuscripts Collection, retaining their box and folder numbers as originally assigned.
An accretion was added in March 2019. The accession number associated with this gift is 2019.019.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions. Appointments are necessary to consult manuscript and archival materials.
Biographical Note
De Coursey Fales (1888-1966) was a lawyer, banker, collector, bibliophile and yachtsman. In the last years of his life, Fales devoted himself full-time to collecting. Fales' collecting started with Walter Scott materials, and around that core, his collection grew to around 50,000 items pertaining to various authors spanning the 18th and 20th centuries. He began donating parts of that collection to New York University in 1957, and portions of his collection were also donated to the New York Public Library, Manhattan College, and the Morgan Library (of which he was a life fellow).
Scope and Content Note
The Fales Manuscripts Collection consists of correspondence, manuscripts, drawings, photographs, realia, ephemera, and other materials by and about primarily English and American authors from 1700 to the present. The collection is especially strong in materials by Charles Washington Baird, Max Beerbohm, Hilaire Belloc, Arnold Bennett, E. F. Benson, Walter Besant, Paul Blackburn, George Borrow, Cyrus Townsend Brady, John Burroughs, Erskine Caldwell, Hall Caine, Tom Clark, Wilkie Collins, Marie Corelli, Pearl Marie Teresa Craigie, George Cruikshank, Esmond Samuel De Beer, Walter De la Mare, Louis Ferdinand Destouches (aka Celine), Charles Dickens, Charles Lutwidge Dodgson (aka Lewis Carroll), George Dowden, Lord Dunsany, Jeffery Farnol, Ronald Firbank, John Galsworthy, Robert Gessner, Allen Ginsberg, Edmund Gosse, Joe Gould, Samuel Greenberg, Christine M. Demain Hammond, Thomas Hardy, Frank Harris, Holbrook Jackson, Letitia Elizabeth Landon, Andrew Lang, Richard Le Gallienne, Harry Lewis, E. V. Lucas, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Arthur Machen, John Masefield, Alice Meynell, A. A. Milne, Mrs. Mary Louisa Molesworth, George Moore, Howard Moss, Jeff Nuttall, Eugene O'Neill, Amelia Opie, Baroness Emmunska Orczy, Sean O'Casey, Max Pemberton, Eden Phillpotts, Arthur Pinero, The Provincetown Players, Anne Thackeray Ritchie, Sir Walter Scott, Isaac Bashevis Singer, Smith and Austen-Leigh Papers, Bram Stoker, William Makepeace Thackeray, Francis Thompson, Giuseppe Verdi, Sir Hugh Walpole, H. G. Wells, Octavia Wilberforce, Oscar Wilde, Thornton Wilder, and Charlotte Yonge. There are special strengths in the Victorian, Edwardian, English 1890s, and Transition Period writers.
The Fales Manuscripts are arranged by size into three groups: Legal; Flat and Dickensiana; and Letter. Sometimes entire discrete collections are included within this collection (see for example the Tom Clark Papers, the Frank Harris Papers, the Provincetown Players Archive).
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
The files are separated by size:
Missing Title
Letter sized.
Legal sized.
Large flat boxes and Dickensiana.
Related Material at the Fales Library and Special Collections
See the avant–garde collections such as Angel Hair, Second Aeon, El Corno Emplumado, C: Comics; the Alfred Berol Collection for Lewis Carroll materials; the Portrait and Theater files for illustrative materials; The Sterling Lord Papers for Beat writers.
Separated Material
There is no information about materials that are associated by provenance to the described materials that have been physically separated or removed.
American literature -- 20th century.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence; Authors, American |y 19th century |v Correspondence.; Authors, English -- 20th century -- Correspondence.; Authors, American |x Correspondence.; American fiction.; American drama |y 20th century |x History and criticism.; Printed ephemera.; American literature |y 19th century.; Manuscripts for publication.; English literature |y 19th century.; English literature |y 18th century.; Authors, English |y 18th century |v Correspondence.; Theater -- New York (State) -- New York -- History -- 20th century.; English fiction.; Authors, English |x Correspondence.; Authors, English |y 19th century |v Correspondence.; English literature |y 20th century.; Galley proofs.; Photographs.; Drawings; Theater |z Massachusetts |z Provincetown |x History |y 20th century.; Correspondence.; Scrapbooks.; De la Mare, Walter, 1873-1956; Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron, 1803-1873; Lucas, E. V. (Edward Verrall), 1868-1938; Masefield, John, 1878-1967; Machen, Arthur, 1863-1947; Milne, A. A. (Alan Alexander), 1882-1956; Meynell, Alice Christiana Thompson, 1847-1922; Moore, George, 1852-1933; Molesworth, Mrs., 1839-1921; Nuttall, Jeff; Moss, Howard, 1922-1987; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964; Orczy, Emmuska Orczy, Baroness, 1865-1947; Opie, Amelia Alderson, 1769-1853; Phillpotts, Eden, 1862-1960; Pemberton, Max, Sir, 1863-1950; Pinero, Arthur Wing, Sir, 1855-1934; Provincetown Players; Ritchie, Anne Thackeray, 1837-1919; Scott, Walter, Sir, 1771-1832; Singer, Isaac Bashevis, 1904-1991; Smith and Austen-Leigh Papers; Stoker, Bram, 1847-1912; Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863; Thompson, Francis, 1859-1907; Yonge, Charlotte Mary, 1823-1901; Verdi, Giuseppe, 1813-1901; Walpole, Hugh, Sir, 1884-1941; Wells, H. G. (Herbert George), 1866-1946; Wilberforce, Octavia, 1888-1963; Wilde, Oscar, 1854-1900; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878; Hobbes, John Oliver (Craigie, Pearl Mary Teresa Richards, 1867-1906), 1867-1906; Corelli, Marie, 1855-1924; Collins, Wilkie, 1824-1889; Clark, Tom, 1941-; Caine, Hall, Sir, 1853-1931; Burroughs, John, 1837-1921; Dunsany, Edward John Moreton Drax Plunkett, Baron, 1878-1957; Caldwell, Erskine, 1903-1987; Dowden, George; Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge, 1832-1898; Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870; Céline, Louis-Ferdinand, 1894-1961; De Beer, Esmond Samuel, 1895-1990; Gould, Joe, 1889-1957; Greenberg, Samuel, 1893-1917; Gosse, Edmund, 1849-1928; Galsworthy, John, 1867-1933; Gessner, Robert, 1907-1968; Farnol, Jeffery, 1878-1952; Firbank, Ronald, 1886-1926; Le Gallienne, Richard, 1866-1947; Lewis, Harry; L. E. L. (Letitia Elizabeth Landon), 1802-1838; Lang, Andrew, 1844-1912; Harris, Frank, 1855-1931; Jackson, Holbrook, 1874-1948; Hammond, Christine M. Demain, fl. 1886-1910; Hardy, Thomas, 1840-1928; Ginsberg, Allen, 1926-1997; Baird, Charles W. (Charles Washington), 1828-1887; Besant, Walter, Sir, 1836-1901; Blackburn, Paul; Borrow, George Henry, 1803-1881; Brady, Cyrus Townsend, 1861-1920; Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956; Belloc, Hilaire, 1870-1953; Bennett, Arnold, 1867-1931; Benson, E. F. (Edward Frederic), 1867-1940
- Legal size boxes, 47367
  - Ainsworth, William Harrison, undated; 47642 (Box 195, Folder 1)
  - Allen, Grant, undated; 47641 (Box 195, Folder 2)
  - Anderson, Sherwood, undated; 47640 (Box 195, Folder 3)
  - Anonymous: MS. Abode of the Spiteful Fairy, undated; 47639 (Box 195, Folder 4a)
  - Anonymous: MS. Covetous Franz, undated; 47638 (Box 195, Folder 4b)
  - Anonymous: MS. The Marble King and the Golden Sprite, undated; 47637 (Box 195, Folder 4c)
  - Anonymous: MS. Married, undated; 47636 (Box 195, Folder 4)
  - Anonymous: MS. Spite, undated; 47635 (Box 195, Folder 4e)
  - Anonymous: MS. You're No Gentleman, 'Sir', undated; 47634 (Box 195, Folder 4)
  - Arnold, Edwin, Sir, undated; 47633 (Box 195, Folder 5a)
  - Ayden, Erje: MS. Matador, 1997; 138384 (Box 196, Folder 1)
  - Bacheller, Irving: The Unhappy Shoat [autographed], undated; 47632 (Box 195, Folder 5b)
  - Baker, Ernest A.: The Poetical Origin of English Prose Fiction, 1907; 47631 (Box 195, Folder 6a)
  - Bayard, William: 1 Letter, undated; 47630 (Box 195, Folder 6b)
  - Beerbohm, Max, Sir (1872-1956): 1 Letter, undated; 47629 (Box 195, Folder 6c)
  - Behan, Brendan: 1 Letter, undated; 47628 (Box 195, Folder 6)
  - Bradshaw, Robert: 1 Letter, undated; 47627 (Box 195, Folder 6e)
  - Beresford, Charles: 1 Letter, undated; 47626 (Box 195, Folder 6)
  - Blackburn, Paul: 3 T.L.s and 1 A.L.s to Sampieri, Frank; 5 T.L.s to Weiners, John; 1 to "Lou"; 1 to [Harold Decker?], undated; 47625 (Box 195, Folder 7a)
  - Blackburn, Paul: Poem MS. Cafe at Night, undated; 47624 (Box 195, Folder 7b)
  - Blackmore, R. D.: 1 Letter, undated; 47623 (Box 195, Folder 8)
  - Blake, William: On Homer's Poetry, ca. 1820-1821; 47622 (Box 195, Folder 9)
  - Blessington, Marguerite (1789-1849): MS., undated; 47621 (Box 195, Folder 10)
  - Bonaparte, Jerome: 1 Letter, undated; 47620 (Box 195, Folder 11a)
  - Boughton, George Henry (1834-1905): Menu, undated; 47619 (Box 195, Folder 11b)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. As Between Gentlemen, undated; 47618 (Box 195, Folder 12a)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. Crooked to the Last, undated; 47617 (Box 195, Folder 12b)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. The Crotalus, undated; 47616 (Box 195, Folder 12c)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. The Dowry of Waterloo, undated; 47615 (Box 195, Folder 12)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. The Eagle of the Empire, undated; 47614 (Box 195, Folder 12e)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. In the Land of Burnt Out Fires, undated; 47613 (Box 195, Folder 12)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. A Little Child Shall Lead Them, undated; 47612 (Box 195, Folder 12g)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. Pride of Race, undated; 47611 (Box 195, Folder 12h)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. The Puff, undated; 47610 (Box 195, Folder 12i)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. The Victor's Return, undated; 47609 (Box 195, Folder 12j)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. When the Sun Stood Still, undated; 47608 (Box 195, Folder 12k)
  - Brady, Cyrus Townsend (1861-1920): MS. unidentified, undated; 47607 (Box 195, Folder 12l)
  - Brayton, Stephen: MS. General Armstrong, undated; 47606 (Box 197, Folder 1a)
  - Brayton, Stephen: MS. Ritch Carpenter's Daughter, undated; 47605 (Box 197, Folder 1b)
  - Bryant, William Cullen: 1 Letter, undated; 47604 (Box 197, Folder 1c)
  - Burchett, Josiah (1666?-1746), undated; 47603 (Box 197, Folder 2)
  - Burns, Robert (1786-1857): MS., undated; 47602 (Box 197, Folder 3)
  - Campbell, Thomas (1777-1844) [see also Standard Size], undated; 47601 (Box 197, Folder 4)
  - Carey, Matthew and Son, undated; 47600 (Box 197, Folder 5)
  - Chambers, Robert William (1865-1933), undated; 47599 (Box 197, Folder 6a)
  - Chambers, Robert William (1865-1933): MS. Step In, pp. 482-598, undated; 47598 (Box 197, Folder 6b)
  - Clark, Tom (1941- ): Correspondence to, undated; 47597 (Box 197, Folder 7)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne (1835-1910): 1 MAT. "American Claimant," (Inc.), undated; 47596 (Box 197, Folder 8)
  - Cooper, James Fenimore, undated; 47595 (Box 197, Folder 9)
  - Craigie, Pearl M. T. (Richards): Clippings [see also Standard Size], undated; 47594 (Box 197, Folder 10)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Letters, 1877-1899; 47593 (Box 198, Folder 1)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Letters, 1900-1905; 47592 (Box 198, Folder 2)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Letters, 1906-1908; 47591 (Box 198, Folder 3)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Letters, 1909; 47590 (Box 198, Folder 4)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Letters, 1910; 47589 (Box 198, Folder 5)
  - Corelli, Marie: Letters, 1911-1917; 47588 (Box 198, Folder 6)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Letters, 1918-1922; 47587 (Box 198, Folder 7)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Letters, 1923-1924; 47586 (Box 198, Folder 8)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Letters [undated], 47585 (Box 198, Folder 9)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): MSS. and Miscellaneous, undated; 47584 (Box 198, Folder 10)
  - Corelli, Marie (1855-1924): Clippings, undated; 47583 (Box 198, Folder 11)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence to Samperi, Frank, undated; 47582 (Box 199, Folder 1)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence to Taggart, John, 1971-1974; 47581 (Box 199, Folder 2)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence to Weil, James, 1963-1966; 47580 (Box 199, Folder 3a)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence to Weil, James, 1967-1968; 47579 (Box 199, Folder 3b)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence to Weil, James, 1969-1971; 47578 (Box 199, Folder 3c)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence to Weil, James, 1972-1973; 47577 (Box 200, Folder 1)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence from Eshleman, Clayton, 1964-1965; 47576 (Box 200, Folder 2a)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence from Eshleman, Clayton, 1966; 47575 (Box 200, Folder 2b)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence from Eshleman, Clayton, 1967-1968; 47574 (Box 200, Folder 2c)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence from Weil, James, 1966; 47573 (Box 200, Folder 3a)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence from Weil, James, 1967-1969; 47572 (Box 200, Folder 3b)
  - Corman, Cid: Correspondence: Business Correspondence to N.Y.U., undated; 47571 (Box 200, Folder 4)
  - Cruikshank, George (1792-1878): Drawing, undated; 47570 (Box 201, Folder 1)
  - Cruikshank, George (1792-1878): Cruikshankiana, undated; 47569 (Box 201, Folder 2)
  - Dalyrymple, Alexander, undated; 47568 (Box 201, Folder 3)
  - De la Ramee, Louise: to Chapman, F. [Chapman & Holly], undated; 47567 (Box 201, Folder 4)
  - Dibdin, Charles: The Bee Proffers Honey, undated; 47566 (Box 201, Folder 5)
  - [Dickens, Charles] Mayer, Brantz: C.D.'s American Tour, undated; 47565 (Box 201, Folder 6)
  - Dickensiana: Jerrold Memorial Fund, undated; 47564 (Box 201, Folder 7)
  - Dickens, Charles (1812-1870): Theatricals, undated; 47563 (Box 201, Folder 8a)
  - Dreiser, Theodore: autographed contract, undated; 47562 (Box 201, Folder 8b)
  - Durrell, Lawrence (1912- ): MS. Island Fugue, undated; 47561 (Box 201, Folder 8c)
  - Egg, Augustus, undated; 47560 (Box 201, Folder 9)
  - Enslin, Theodore: Correspondence to A-J, undated; 47559 (Box 201, Folder 10a)
  - Enslin, Theodore: Correspondence to/from Lewis, Harry, undated; 47558 (Box 201, Folder 10b)
  - Enslin, Theodore: Correspondence to/from M-Z, Unidentified, undated; 47557 (Box 201, Folder 10c)
  - Farnol, Jeffery (1878-1952): MS. The Blasted Oak, undated; 47556 (Box 201, Folder 11a)
  - Farnol, Jeffery (1878-1952): MS. The Dispatch Rider, undated; 47555 (Box 201, Folder 11b)
  - Farnol, Jeffery (1878-1952): MS. The Island of Heart's Delight, undated; 47554 (Box 201, Folder 11c)
  - Farnol, Jeffery (1878-1952): MS. The Sheriff of Nottingham, undated; 47553 (Box 201, Folder 11)
  - Farnol, Jeffery (1878-1952): MSS. [unidentified]: "But I stood there listening ..."; Dramatis Personae: Viscount Ravenshoe, ..., undated; 47552 (Box 201, Folder 11e)
  - Farnol, Jeffery (1878-1952): MS. [unidentified]: "As they entered the college Bellow perceived ...", undated; 47551 (Box 201, Folder 11)
  - Firbank, Ronald: MS. [Notes], undated; 47550 (Box 201, Folder 12a)
  - Firbank, Ronald: MS. When Widows Love, undated; 47549 (Box 201, Folder 12b)
  - Forster, John, undated; 47548 (Box 201, Folder 13)
  - Dowden, George: Correspondence: A-F, undated; 47547 (Box 202, Folder 1a)
  - Dowden, George: Correspondence: G-H, undated; 47546 (Box 202, Folder 1b)
  - Dowden, George: Correspondence: Georgakis, Dan, 1967-1973; 47545 (Box 202, Folder 1c)
  - Dowden, George: Correspondence: Houe´dard, Dom Sylvester, [Editor, Openings], 1963-1974; 47544 (Box 202, Folder 2a)
  - Dowden, George: Correspondence: L-N, undated; 47543 (Box 202, Folder 2b)
  - Dowden, George: Correspondence: R-Z, undated; 47542 (Box 202, Folder 2c)
  - Gallatin, Albert: Correspondence, undated; 47541 (Box 203, Folder 1a)
  - Gallatin, Albert: Photocopies and Miscellaneous, undated; 47540 (Box 203, Folder 1b)
  - Galt, John, undated; 47539 (Box 203, Folder 2)
  - Garrick, David, undated; 47538 (Box 203, Folder 3)
  - Gaskell, Elizabeth, undated; 47537 (Box 203, Folder 4)
  - Ginsberg, Allen: MSS. The Change; Poem, undated; 47536 (Box 203, Folder 5a)
  - Ginsberg, Allen: MS. Wichita Vortex Sutra, undated; 47535 (Box 203, Folder 5b)
  - Gordimer, Nadine: [see also New American Library], undated; 47534 (Box 203, Folder 6)
  - Greenberg, Samuel (Bernard) (1894-1917), undated; 47533 (Box 203, Folder 7a)
  - Greenberg, Samuel (Bernard) (1894-1917): MSS. Apology Sonnets, undated; 47532 (Box 203, Folder 7b)
  - Grieve, Christopher M.: Correspondence: 2 A.L.s; MSS. Caratid Cornucopius; Robert Burns, undated; 47531 (Box 203, Folder 8)
  - Grieve, Christopher M.: MS. In Memoriam James Joyce 1, undated; 47530 (Box 204, Folder 1a)
  - Grieve, Christopher M.: MS. In Memoriam James Joyce 2, undated; 47529 (Box 204, Folder 1b)
  - Grieve, Christopher M.: MS. Scottish Proletarian Literature, undated; 47528 (Box 204, Folder 1c)
  - Grigson, Soffy, undated; 47527 (Box 204, Folder 2)
  - Guiterman, Arthur: Poems [unpublished]; Poems [Pre-1909], undated, pre-1909; 47526 (Box 204, Folder 3a)
  - Guiterman, Arthur: MS. Poems [Early New York, not included in Old New York], undated; 47525 (Box 204, Folder 3b)
  - Guiterman, Arthur: MS. Miscellaneous, undated; 47524 (Box 204, Folder 3c)
  - Haggard, Henry Rider, Sir (1856-1925), undated; 47523 (Box 204, Folder 4)
  - Hanley, James (1901- ), undated; 47522 (Box 204, Folder 5)
  - Hardy, Thomas: MS., undated; 47521 (Box 204, Folder 6)
  - Harris, Frank (1855-1931): copyright data, undated; 47520 (Box 205, Folder 1a)
  - Harris, Frank (1855-1931), undated; 47519 (Box 205, Folder 1b)
  - Hawthorne, Julian, undated; 47518 (Box 205, Folder 2)
  - Hawthorne, Nathaniel, undated; 47517 (Box 205, Folder 3)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, undated; 47516 (Box 205, Folder 4)
  - Hewlett, Maurice: MS. Anemones, undated; 47515 (Box 205, Folder 5a)
  - Hewlett, Maurice: MS. Chelsea's Place, undated; 47514 (Box 205, Folder 5b)
  - Hewlett, Maurice: MS. La Petite Personne, undated; 47513 (Box 205, Folder 5c)
  - Hitchens, Robert: Music to Law of the Sands, undated; 47512 (Box 205, Folder 6)
  - Hood, Thomas: MS. The Life and Times of Eugene Aram [newsprint], undated; 47511 (Box 205, Folder 7)
  - Hook, Theodore Edward: MS. Life of Mathews the Elder, undated; 47510 (Box 205, Folder 8)
  - Humphrey, Eliza Margaret J. (Gallan), undated; 47509 (Box 205, Folder 9)
  - Huxley, Aldous, undated; 47508 (Box 205, Folder 10)
  - International Writers Conference 1962, 47507 (Box 206, Folder 1a-1d)
  - James, Henry, undated; 47506 (Box 206, Folder 2a)
  - Jerrold, Blanchard, undated; 47505 (Box 206, Folder 2b)
  - Johnson, Edward, undated; 47504 (Box 206, Folder 2c)
  - Joyce, James: Miscellaneous; Portrait of James Joyce [BBC 1950], undated; 1950; 47503 (Box 206, Folder 3)
  - Kingsley, Henry, undated; 47502 (Box 206, Folder 4)
  - Kipling, Rudyard: MS. Fugitive Verses; Musical Score: Recessional, undated; 47501 (Box 206, Folder 5)
  - Kunitz, Stanley: MS. The Long Boat, undated; 47500 (Box 206, Folder 6)
  - Lewis, Harry: Correspondence from Cid Corman [see also Lewis file], undated; 47499 (Box 206, Folder 7)
  - Lewis, Sinclair: Introduction to 4 Days on the Webetuck, undated; 47498 (Box 206, Folder 8)
  - Lionni, Paolo, undated; 47497 (Box 206, Folder 9)
  - Livingston, William (1723-1790), undated; 47496 (Box 206, Folder 10a)
  - Locke, William John, undated; 47495 (Box 206, Folder 10b)
  - Lytton, Edward Bulwer Lytton, Baron (1803-1873) (Edward George Earle): MS. Love and Parliament, Canto Second, undated; 47494 (Box 206, Folder 10c)
  - McFee, William: MS. The Merchant Marine and the Young Fellow, undated; 47493 (Box 206, Folder 11)
  - MacKenzie, Colin [friend of Sir Walter Scott], undated; 47492 (Box 206, Folder 12)
  - Mather, Cotton, undated; 47491 (Box 206, Folder 13a)
  - Mather, Increase, undated; 47490 (Box 206, Folder 13b)
  - Mather, Samuel, undated; 47489 (Box 206, Folder 13c)
  - Maugham, W. Somerset: Galleys: The Vessel of Wrath [5 March 1931], 47488 (Box 206, Folder 14)
  - Maupassant, Guy: MS. Le Jour de Paul, undated; 47487 (Box 206, Folder 15)
  - Melvill, Thomas, undated; 47486 (Box 206, Folder 16)
  - Meredith, George (1828-1909): George Meredith / Alice Meynell Letters, 1896-1909; 47485 (Box 207, Folder 1)
  - Meredith, George (1828-1909): George Meredith / Alice Meynell Letters [essay by A.M. removed from above], 1896-1909; 47484 (Box 207, Folder 2)
  - Methuen, Paul Sanford, baron (1845-1932), undated; 47483 (Box 207, Folder 3)
  - Mitchison, Naomi (1897-1999) (nee´ Naomi Margaret Hablane), undated; 47482 (Box 207, Folder 4)
  - Mitford, Mary Russell (1786-1855): MS. The Lost Pearl, undated; 47481 (Box 207, Folder 5)
  - Morris, May: Memories of May Morris, by Sir Basil Blackwell [see also Standard Size], undated; 47480 (Box 207, Folder 6)
  - Morrison, Arthur (1863-1945), undated; 47479 (Box 207, Folder 7)
  - Morse, Samuel F. P., undated; 47478 (Box 207, Folder 8)
  - Moulton, Hugh Fletcher: MS. Untitled p. 1-32 [see also Standard Size for continued], undated; 47477 (Box 207, Folder 9)
  - Jackson, Holbrook: Correspondence: Business Agreements, undated; 47476 (Box 208, Folder 1)
  - Jackson, Holbrook: MS. The Beau, undated; 47475 (Box 208, Folder 2a)
  - Jackson, Holbrook: MS. Biographia, undated; 47474 (Box 208, Folder 2b)
  - Jackson, Holbrook: MS. Biography: Carpenter, Edward, undated; 47473 (Box 208, Folder 3a)